Stuart Gerry Brown Papers
Stuart Gerry Brown Papers
1934-1968
Brown, Stuart Gerry, 1912-1991
14 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, educator, specialist in American studies, political consultant. Collection includes correspondence, writings, and papers relating to the "Draft Stevenson" movement of the 1960 U.S. Presidential campaign. Correspondents include Averell Harriman, Clinton Rossiter, Arthur Schlesinger Jr., and Adlai Stevenson. Writings include addresses, radio speeches, and short pieces for and about Stevenson. Also three scrapbooks of clippings on Stevenson.
148872
Biographical History
Stuart Gerry Brown (1912-1991) was an American author, educator, and political consultant. He taught at Syracuse University for nearly twenty years.
Born April 13, 1912, in Buffalo, New York, to Charles H., Jr. and Edith (Brown) Brown, he received his A.B. degree from Amherst College in 1934 and his Ph.D. from Princeton University in 1937. In 1937 he became an English instructor at the University of Wisconsin. In 1940, he went to Grinnell College as an associate professor of English and was a full professor of English when he left Grinnell in 1947 to become a professor of Citizenship and American Culture at the Maxwell Graduate School of Citizenship and Public Affairs at Syracuse University. During 1961-1962 and 1964-1965, he was visiting professor at the East-West Cultural Center at the University of Hawaii. In August of 1965, Mr. Brown resigned from Syracuse University to become graduate professor of American Studies at the East-West Center.
Brown was a Democratic state committeeman in Iowa, vice president of Americans for Democratic Action in New York State, a campaign aide to Adlai. E. Stevenson and founder of the Stevenson for President Movement in Onondaga County (N.Y.).
He is the author of The First Republicans (1954), Conscience in Politics (1961), Jefferson (1963); and (with C. Peltier) Government in Our Republic (1960). He is the editor of We Hold These Truths, 2nd edition (1948), Great Issues (1948), The Social Philosophy of Josiah Royce (1950), The Religious Philosophy of Josiah Royce (1952), The Autobiography of James Monroe (1959). With Wright Thomas he edited Reading Poems (1941) and Reading Prose (1952), and with H. Bragdon and S. McCutcheon he edited Frame of Government (1962). He also has contributed articles and book reviews to many educational reviews and journals.
Brown had one daughter, Antoinette Franchot, by his first marriage to Katharine Franchot, and two sons, Stuart Gerry and Thomas Stuart, by his second marriage to Mildred Kraus.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Stuart Gerry Brown Papers collection is divided into five groups: correspondence, memorabilia, student records, writings, and Adlai E. Stevenson Papers on the 1960 Stevenson draft Movement.
Correspondence, 1934-1968, consisting of letters to and from friends, colleagues, publishers and students, The letters are concerned with the editing and publication of his writings and with politics, education, job offers, students' problems and personal matters. Significant correspondents include the Chautauqua Institution, Henry Steele Commager, Felix Frankfurter, Averill Harriman, Lyndon Johnson, John F. Kennedy, Archibald MacLeish, Patsy Takemoto Mink, Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Frank Piskor, George Santayana, Arthur Schlesinger, Adlai Stevenson, William P. Tolley, Harry S. Truman, and Eleanor Roosevelt. Also of interest is Brown's correspondence in 1967-1968 with Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. with regard to the 1968 presidential campaign and the candidacy of Robert Kennedy.
There is additional correspondence of significance in the Adlai E. Stevenson Papers on the 1960 Stevenson draft Movement.
Memorabilia, 1947-1967, includes Aden and Middle East material, biographical material, brochures and catalogues, committees, course descriptions, expense accounts, miscellaneous printed material, photographs, dinner and round table programs, Adlai E. Stevenson mimeographed addresses and statements and news clippings about Adlai E. Stevenson, arranged in that order. There are a few news clippings about Brown's speeches.
Student records, 1958-1968 include individual student programs, papers written by students and covering letters.
Writings, 1940-1968, include addresses, articles, book reviews, books, a citation, a course description, a course outline, essays, lectures, letters to the editor, notes, a radio discussion, radio speeches, reports, short pieces about Adlai E. Stevenson, writings for Adlai E. Stevenson and writings of others. Most of the writings are in manuscript form. Research material is included for the book Conscience in Politics and for speeches of Adlai E. Stevenson. Among the writings by others, an untitled article on the 1960 campaign by Gerald W. Johnson, and Theodore Sands' article, "The Unfinished Business of the '52 Campaign: Foreign Policy" should be mentioned. One speech that Brown wrote for Robert Kennedy's use in the spring of 1968 is included in the addresses. The articles deal with both historical topics and contemporary political issues. There are seven book reviews, including reviews of biographies of Adlai Stevenson and Robert Kennedy. There is also one item by another author, S.C. Hsieh.
The Adlai E. Stevenson Papers on the 1960 Stevenson draft Movement include three folders of chronologically arranged correspondence and two folders of writings by Stuart Gerry Brown. The remaining material, in consecutively numbered folders, consists of transcripts of interviews, reports and correspondence. The first of the numbered folders contains a descriptive calendar of the contents of the numbered series. This part of the collection is maintained in original order, with the folders titled and numbered by Brown himself.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender/recipient. Student records are arranged alphabetically by student name. Writings are subdivided by type, with material relating to Adlai Stevenson filed separately at the end in original order. Within each group, the writings are arranged alphabetically by title. Writings of others are arranged alphabetically by author.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Brown, Stuart Gerry, 1912-1991.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Mink, Patsy T., 1927-2002.; Rossiter, Clinton, 1917-1970.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D., Jr. (Franklin Delano), 1914-1988.; Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Tolley, William Pearson, 1900-1996.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Amherst College.; Democratic Party (U.S.); Grinnell College.; Grolier Society.; Library of Congress.; Macmillan Publishing Company.; Syracuse University.; University of Hawaii (Honolulu); United States. -- Work Projects Administration.; Authors, American.; Educators -- United States.; Legislators -- United States.; Political campaigns.; Political consultants -- United States.; Articles.; Book reviews.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Essays.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Educators.; Governors.; Political consultants.; Senators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Stuart Gerry Brown, 1967-68.
Autobiography manuscript, gift of Robert J. Wilson, 2020.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Acheson, Dean G., 1954 (Box 1)
  - Ahlberg, Clark, 1950; 1955 (Box 1)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1953; 1955,; 1957 (Box 1)
  - Allen, James Edward Jr., 1954 (Box 1)
  - Aloia, Vincent, 1954-1955; 1962,; 1966 (Box 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1956; 1962 (Box 1)
  - The American Peoples Encyclopedia, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1968 (Box 1)
  - American Political Science Association, 1957 (Box 1)
  - American Scholar, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Amherst College, 1947-1956; 1962-1968; includes Gail Kennedy, Edwin Charles Rozwenc, George Rogers Taylor, and George F. Whicher; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Amirthanoyagam, Guy, 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Paul Shipman, 1954 (Box 1)
  - The Anniston Star, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Appleby, Paul H., See Syracuse University; State of New York Division of the Budget.
  - Armed Forces Staff College, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Thurman Wesley, 1957 (Box 1)
  - The Asia Foundation, 1957 (Box 1)
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1949; 1957 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1946; 1955 (Box 1)
  - A, miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Bain, Harry, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Stephen Kemp, See Syracuse University.
  - Baker, Donald G., 1962-1968 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Willard, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Ballentine, Duncan, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Banwell, Mary R., See Grinnell College; Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Bartlett, Kenneth Gill, See Syracuse University.
  - Barron's Educational Series, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Beach, Joseph Warren, 1947; Consists of letter of recommendation to Beach; See also Kroeger, Frederick P. (Box 1)
  - Bender, George H., 1953 (Box 1)
  - Bergstrom, George W., 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Berle, Adolf Augustus, 1951-1952; 1957 (Box 1)
  - Berstein, Melvin, 1952-1956; 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Bertsche, Frank T., 1952-1955; undated (Box 1)
  - Bickal, Robert R., 1952; 1962 (Box 1)
  - Biddle, Francis, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Bingham, Johnathon Brewster, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Blair, William McCormick, Jr., 1954-1965; undated (Box 1)
  - Blick, Thomas Edward Jr., 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1953; 1956 (Box 1)
  - Bodkin, Robert G., 1954-1955; 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Booz, Allen & Hamilton, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Bradford, Curtis Baker, 1947-1950 (Box 1)
  - Bragdon, Henry, 1957; 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Brant, Irving Newton, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Brautigam, Herman, 1954; 1963,; 1966 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Charles H. Jr., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Brown, James, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Sherman, 1950-1951; undated (Box 1)
  - Butler, Paul M., See Democratic National Committee.
  - Bye, Carl R., See Syracuse University.
  - B, Miscellaneous, includes photographs (Box 2)
  - Canfield, Cass, See Harper & Brothers Publishers.
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1955; 1963 (Box 2)
  - Case, Everett Needham, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
  - Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange between East and West, 1962-1967; includes Alezander Spoehr (Box 2)
  - Center for Information on America, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Chapman, Chanler A., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Charles Scribner's Son, 1948-1949; 1953-1957 (Box 2)
  - Chautauqua, 1948; 1952-1956 (Box 2)
  - Citizen-Advertiser, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Clampitt, Amy, See Oxford University Press
  - Clapp, Harold, See Grinnell College.
  - Clark, Harry Hayden, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Cleveland, James Harlan, 1957; 1961-1965 (Box 2)
  - Commager, Henry Steele, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America Inc., 1943 (Box 2)
  - Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1951-1954; 1957-1959,; 1962-1964 (Box 2)
  - The Community Church of New York, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Cooke, Robert J., 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - Cooper, John Sherman, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Cord, Robert, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Cornell University, 1952-1956; 1968,; undated (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Fina Goff, See Syracuse University; Payne Memorial Volume
  - Cressey, George Babcock, See Syracuse University.
  - Cuningham, Charles E., 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Curti, Merle Eugene
  - C, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - D. C. Health and Company, 1948; 1954,; 1957 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Chester Charles, 1948 (Box 2)
    See also Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Davis, Hallie Flanagan, See Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Day, Arthur Grove, See University of Hawaii.
  - Democratic County Committee of Onondaga, 1952-1955 (Box 2)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1953-1959; includes Paul M. Butler and Stephen Arnold Mitchell (Box 2)
  - Democratic State Committee of New York, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Dockham, Betty, 1952-1953; 1956 (Box 2)
  - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1954; 1957 (Box 2)
  - Dougherty, Richard A., 1958 (Box 2)
  - Doyle, James E., 1962-1964 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Press, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Dunner, Joseph, See Grinnell College; Payne Memorial Volume.
  - D, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Eberlein, Roxanne, See Stevenson, Adlai.
  - Ehrlich, John, 1952-1956; 1968 (Box 2)
  - Elfin, Melvin, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Elliot, G. Roy, 1948-1954; 1962 (Box 2)
  - Emma Willard School, 1949; 1954 (Box 2)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Engler, Bob, 1950-1957 (Box 2)
  - Ethics, 1953-1955; 1962-1967 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Carol, 1965-1967; See also Stevenson, Adlai. (Box 3)
  - Evans, Frank B. III, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Everton, John Scott, 1948-1950; 1968 (Box 3)
  - E, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Faigle, Eric H., See Syracuse University.
  - Fairchild, Thomas E., 1952 (Box 3)
  - Falk, Sawyer, See Syracuse University.
  - Farnen, Russell F., 1962-1963; 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Fausold, Martin, 1955-1957; 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - The Field Foundation, Inc., 1962 (Box 3)
  - Field, Ruth, 1963; undated (Box 3)
  - Fields, Dorothy Louise, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Finkelstein, Louis, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Finletter, Thomas Knight, 1954-1962; 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Fiser, Webb S., 1953-1954; 1968 (Box 3)
  - Foerster, Norman, 1947-1950 (Box 3)
  - Forbes, John V. G., 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Foster, Charles Howell, 1945-1948; 1952-1954,; 1964,; undated (Box 3)
  - Franchot, Antoinette, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1954 (Box 3)
  - French, Sidney James, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - Friedrich, Carl J., 1948-1949; 1953 (Box 3)
  - Fritchey, Clayton, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Fritschler, A. Lee, See Syracuse University.
  - Frost, Robert, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Fulbright, James William, 1954 (Box 3)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1953-1956; includes William Spencer Litterick (Box 3)
  - F, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Gabriel, Ralph Henry, 1948-1949 (Box 3)
  - Garrison, Lloyd K., 1956-1958 (Box 3)
  - Gaus, John M., 1949; 1951-1954 (Box 3)
  - General Electric Company, 1948-1949 (Box 3)
  - Gnoza, Edward, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Goodwin, Paul, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Gray, Phillip H., 1948 (Box 3)
  - Gray, Yohma, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Grinnell College, 1947-1952; undated (Box 3)
  - Grinnell College, 1953-1956; 1962-1964,; 1967-1968; includes Mary R. Banwell, Harold Clapp, Joseph Dunner, Neal William Klausner, Louis V. Phelps, Adeline Pruyn, Herman Salinger, Samuel Stevens, and Earl D. Strong (Box 4)
  - Grolier Incorporated, 1957-1965; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - G, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Hall, James Norman, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Hallie, Phillip, 1947-1951; 1966 (Box 4)
  - Halstead, Anna Roosevelt, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Hamilton, Charles G., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Hamilton College, 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Harcourt, Brace & Company, Inc., 1946-1948; 1955-1956,; 1964 (Box 4)
  - Hare, Raymond Arthur, See Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Haring, Douglas G., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1947-1948; 1951-1957,; 1961-1962; includes Cass Canfield (Box 4)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - Harriman, Averell W., 1954; 1957-1958,; 1962 (Box 4)
  - Harrison, T. Carter (Mrs.), 1962 (Box 4)
  - Hart, Donn V., See Syracuse University.
  - Harvard University, 1947-1950; 1953-1954,; 1966,; undated (Box 4)
  - Harvard University Press, 1948-1950; 1955-1957 (Box 4)
  - Hayes, Ann, See Syracuse University.
  - Heath, John R., 1954 (Box 4)
  - Henry Holt & Company, Inc., 1947; includes Allen Tate (Box 4)
  - Henry Regnery Company, 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - Henry, Robert, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Hickenlooper, Bourke Blackmore, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Hicks, Grantville, 1953 (Box 4)
  - The Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1962-1967 (Box 4)
  - Hocking, William Ernest, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Hoes, Laurence Gouverner, 1952-1957; undated (Box 4)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Houghton, Mifflin Company, 1951-1952; 1955-1957 (Box 4)
  - Hovey, Richard B., 1952 (Box 4)
  - H, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Institute of Ethics, 1962; 1966-1968 (Box 4)
  - Ives, Elizabeth Stevenson "Buffie", 1965 (Box 5)
  - Ives, Irving McNeil, 1953; undated (Box 5)
  - I, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - J. J. Little & Ives Co., Inc., 1960 (Box 5)
  - James, William, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1955 (Box 5)
  - Jewish Community Center of Syracuse, Inc., 1962 (Box 5)
  - John C. Winston Company, 1950-1951 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Albert Edward, 1951-1952; 1956,; undated (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Walter, 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Jones, Alexander F., 1952; inlcudes clippings (Box 5)
  - Jones, Howard L., See New York State Council for the Social Studies.
  - Jones, Louis Clark, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
  - J, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Kaufman, Ralph J., 1948-1951 (Box 5)
  - Keating, Kenneth B., 1953 (Box 5)
  - Kefauver, Estes, 1956; 1960 (Box 5)
  - Kendrick, John H., 1947-1948 (Box 5)
  - Kennan, George Frost, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Kennedy, Gail, See Amherst College.
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, 1960; 1967 (Box 5)
  - Keohane, Robert E., 1947-1949 (Box 5)
  - Kerr, Florence and Robert Y., 1948-1949; 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Ketcham, Ralph L., 1956-1957; 1962-1968; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Kharas, Ralph E., See Syracuse University.
  - Kinloch, Hector, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Klausner, Neal William, See Grinnell College.
  - Kohn, Hans Dr., 1948-1952; 1965 (Box 5)
  - Kotschnig, Walter Maria, See Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Krinsky, Fred, 1950-1951; 1957,; 1962-1963,; 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Kroeger, Frederick P., 1947; 1956,; 1966 (Box 5)
  - K, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Lattimore, Owen, See Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Lawrence, Ernest, 1950-1951 (Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters, 1947-1948 (Box 5)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1953-1956 (Box 5)
  - Lehman, William C., 1952; 1955 (Box 5)
  - Lerner, Max, 1954-1955; 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1947-1957; 1962-1967,; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Levy, Leonard W., 1963 (Box 5)
  - The Liberal Arts Press, Inc., 1955 (Box 5)
  - Library of Congress, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Linowitz, Sol M., 1956 (Box 5)
  - Litterick, William Spencer, See The Fund for the Advancement of Education.
  - Livingston, Robert, 1948-1950 (Box 5)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot Jr., 1952 (Box 5)
  - Longmans, Green & Co., Inc., 1945-1948 (Box 5)
  - Lubin, Isador, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Lyndenberg, John, 1952; 1956,; 1962-1968 (Box 5)
  - L, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - MacDonald, Jessica, 1947 (Box 6)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Macmillan Company, 1947-1966; undated; 10 folders (Box 6)
  - Mangone, Gerard, See Syracuse University.
  - Marsden, Malcolm and Virginia, 1946; 1949,; 1952,; 1956-1957,; 1962-1963 (Box 6)
  - Martin, Roscoe Coleman, 1949; 1954-1957,; 1964-1967,; undated (Box 6)
  - Mason, Alpheus Thomas, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Massachusetts Teachers Federation, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Maxwell, Amos D., 1953-1954; 1967 (Box 6)
  - McCrea, William S., 1965 (Box 6)
  - McCutcheon, S. P., 1961 (Box 6)
  - McDermott, Edward, 1968 (Box 7)
  - McGowan, Carl, 1952 (Box 7)
  - McGrath, Edward G., 1965-1968; undated (Box 7)
  - Mckeon, Richard P., 1949; 1961-1963 (Box 7)
  - Meiklejohn, Donald, 1962-1968; undated (Box 7)
  - Merrick, Wayne R., 1954-1955; 1963 (Box 7)
  - The Methodist Church Board of Education, 1956; 1963 (Box 7)
  - Milford, Toni, 1948-1950 (Box 7)
  - Miller, Perry, 1948-1955; 1967,; undated (Box 7)
  - Miller, Raymond C., 1962; 1966-1968 (Box 7)
  - Miller, Warren, 1955; 1967 (Box 7)
  - Miller, William A., See Syracuse University; Payne Memorial Volume.
  - Mink, Patsy Takemoto, 1961-1962; includes photograph (Box 7)
  - Minow, Newton Norman, 1956-1958 (Box 7)
  - Missionary Orientation Center, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Mitchell, Stephen Arnold, See Democratic National Committee.
  - Mizener, Arthur Moore, 1950; 1953-1954,; 1957 (Box 7)
  - Monroney, Almer Stillwell "Mike", 1952 (Box 7)
  - Moody, Blair, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Morse, Wayne, 1952-1957; undated (Box 7)
  - Moses, Robert, 1954 (Box 7)
  - The Mosher Family, 1957; 1964; includes Edith, Frederik "Fritz", Alice, Jim, Henry Camp, and Richard (Box 7)
  - Moss, Irwin H., 1954; 1957,; undated (Box 7)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Motwani, Kewal, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Murdock, Kenneth Ballard, 1950; 1954 (Box 7)
  - Murray, Donald, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Mushkat, Jerome, 1952-1964 (Box 7)
  - M, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1955 (Box 7)
  - New England Quarterly, 1945; 1949,; 1952-1955,; undated (Box 7)
  - New York Division of the Budget, See State of New York Division of the Budget.
  - New York State Citizens Council, Inc., 1948 (Box 7)
  - New York State Council for the Social Studies, 1947; includes Howard L. Jones (Box 7)
  - New York State Stevenson for President Committee, 1949; 1956 (Box 7)
  - The New York Times, 1950-1956 (Box 7)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Niemeyer, Carl Anthony, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Noble, Charles C., 1953 (Box 7)
  - Nollen, John Scholte, 1948 (Box 7)
  - N, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - d'Oronzio, Joseph and Wendy, 1963-1966 (Box 7)
  - Owen, David, See Syracuse University.
  - Oxford University Press, 1943; 1947,; 1951-1957,; 1962-1964; includes Amy Clampitt (Box 7)
  - O, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Pacific and Asian Affairs Council, 1967-1968 (Box 7)
  - Palmer, Edward E. "Bob", 1952-1953; 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Payne, Ina C., 1948-1952; 1957,; undated (Box 7)
  - Payne Memorial Volume, 1948-1953; undated; includes Mary R. Banwell, Fina Goff Crawford, Chester Charles Davis, Hallie Flanagan Davis, Joseph Dunner, Carl J. Friedrich, James Norman Hall, Raymond Arthur Hare, John R. Heath, Florence & Robert Kerr, Walter Maria Kotschnig, Owen Lattimore, William A. Miller, John Scholte Nollen, Adeline Pruyn, Hans Simons, James Hamilton St. John, Samuel Stevens, Earl D. Strong, Charles Wright Thomas, Harrison J. Thornton, William Wesley Waymack; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Peace Corps, 1963-1967; undated; includes Bascom Story (Box 8)
  - Peltier, Charles L., 1953-1959; undated (Box 8)
  - Perkins, Dexter, 1957; 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Perry, Charner Marquis, See Ethics; University of Chicago.
  - Persons, Stow Spaulding, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Phelps, Louis V., See Grinnell College.
  - The Philippine Embassy, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Piper, Robert Lewis, 1960-1967; undated; includes photographs (Box 8)
  - Piskor, Frank Peter, See Syracuse University.
  - Porter, Sylvia F., 1957 (Box 8)
  - Powell, Thomas F., 1962-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Price, Roy Arthur, See Syracuse University.
  - Princeton University, 1947; 1953,; 1956-1957,; 1964; includes Princeton Univeristy Press and The Papers of Thomas Jefferson (Box 8)
  - Pruyn, Adeline, See Grinnell College; Payne Memorial Volume.
  - P, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Q, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Random House Inc., 1949; 1955-1956 (Box 8)
  - Remak, Joachim, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Reston, James, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Reynolds, Jack, 1966-1967; includes photographs (Box 8)
  - Reynolds, Keith, 1965-1967 (Box 8)
  - Riehlman, Roy Walter, 1953-1954; 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Riley, William A., 1964-1968; undated (Box 8)
  - Robitscher, Thomas, 1948 (Box 8)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1955-1958 (Box 8)
  - Rockwell, Landon Gale, 1955-1962 (Box 8)
  - Rockwood, Raymond Oxley, 1956; 1962 (Box 8)
  - Roelofs, H. Mark, 1952-1958 (Box 8)
  - Rogers, William B., 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - The Ronald Press Company, 1948-1950; 1955-1956,; 1962 (Box 8)
  - Roosevelt, Anna Eleanor, 1950; 1957-1961 (Box 8)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. Jr., 1954 (Box 8)
  - Rosen, Fred, 1963-1968 (Box 8)
  - Rosenberg, William G., 1964 (Box 8)
  - Rossiter, Clinton, 1953-1957; 1962-1967,; undated (Box 8)
  - Royce, Stephen, 1948-1952 (Box 8)